Jose Guerrero

Software Developer

M: (0423) 663 560 | E: joseguerrerog880@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jose-guerrerog/ | Github: https://github.com/jose-guerrerog/

Portfolio: https://portfolio-pink-seven-87.vercel.app/

SUMMARY

I am a software developer with an Engineering background and over 4 years of commercial experience. My primary expertise is in React.js for front-end development, and I also have a basic foundation in various server-side frameworks, including Django, Node.js, and .Net.

EXPERIENCE

Ansarada Front End Developer

Sep 2021- Apr 2024

- Support in maintaining Monorepo infrastructure and micro frontends using Next.js and Typescript
- Collaborate with UX/UI designers to develop Figma designs for new pages, translating design concepts into seamless and engaging user experiences
- Partner with designers to create reusable React.js components using Storybook, enhancing internal libraries and ensuring consistency across our apps
- Work closely with Product Teams to implement new features for our existing apps using React.is, GraphQL and React Testing Library / Jest for unit testing
- Active participation in Agile sprints, showcasing progress and deliverables every two weeks, fostering transparency and continuous improvement to the whole company

Medius Health Front End Developer

Feb 2021- Sep 2021

- Collaborate with designers to translate Figma designs into functional web applications using React/Redux, Typescript, and GraphQL
- Enhance our mobile app by integrating new features with React Native, improving user experience and expanding functionality
- Partner with backend and machine learning engineers to prototype innovative solutions tailored to client needs, fostering cross-functional teamwork
- Develop robust end-to-end and unit tests using Cypress and React Testing Library / Jest
- Provide backend support with Diango, handling essential tasks such as creating endpoints

Hivexchange Front End Developer

Jan 2020- Jan 2021

• Maintain and enhance our main platform functionalities using React/Redux, Typescript and

- GraphQL to ensure optimal performance and elevate user engagement
- Migrate legacy AngularJS code to React.js to modernize outdated pages and improve maintainability
- Design and implement an internal web application using React.js, Typescript and Material UI to streamline sales operations and boost productivity
- Develop basic API endpoints with Node.js for data integration

Macrovue Front End Developer

Mar 2019 - Dec 2019

- Contribute to the upgrade of the main platform using cutting-edge technologies including React/Redux and Django
- Implement Figma designs to develop new features to enhance overall user experience and functionality
- Develop end-to-end and unit tests with Cypress and Jest to ensure robust application and performance
- Integrate GraphQL mutations and queries across both back-end and front-end sides

Adslot Junior .Net Developer

Jun 2018 - Mar 2019

- Engage in numerous web apps projects using Asp.Net MVC, WebAPI, and React/ Redux for rich user experiences
- Develop unit tests using MSTest and Jest for full-stack projects
- Active participation in Agile sprints, embracing all phases of the software development lifecycle for iterative improvement

EDUCATION

Master of Electrical Engineering University of New South Wales

Mar 2015 - Dec 2016

Achieved a Distinction average